Teerth Patel

Moorpark, CA 93021, willing to relocate | 805-990-0288| teerth1205@gmail.com https://github.com/teerth1205-sketch

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Versatile Full Stack developer, experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming with a background in physics and math tutoring. I enthusiastically bring strong skills in team-building, communication, debugging, data analysis, research and leadership that help any company thrive. I have a deep passion for programming that pushes me to learn and adapt to new environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, Nokogiri, HTML, CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

TaskManager - GitHub | Youtube

A group task manager allowing users to create and organize tasks.

- Utilized Rails to create a Full Stack Task Manager application.
- Integrated Oauth gem to provide 3rd party authentication along with Login/Signup system using cookies, sessions and BCrypt.
- Implemented basic Create, Read, Update, Delete functionality to facilitate viewing, searching and changing info.
- Used Model, View, Controller architecture to ensure separation of concerns and code readability.

Snapstagram - GitHub| Youtube

An Instagram clone allowing for the upload of pictures and writing comments.

- Created a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, photos, and comments.
- Utilized Vanilla ES6 Javascript to develop front-end.
- Handled photo upload using Active Storage in the Rails backend.
- Implemented Object-Oriented Javascript classes to encapsulate data on the frontend.

Runnersland - GitHub | Youtube

A site where users can organize their runs and create events for others to join.

- Used Sinatra gem to develop a full stack CRUD, MVC application.
- Created app using RESTful routing.
- Implemented server side authentication using BCrypt.

EXPERIENCE

Tutoria Remote Software Engineer 06/2020 - Present

Build and maintain components of the website Backend using Ruby on Rails.

Design and adjust Frontend in React with input given from designers.

Sandbox4kids Thousand Oaks, CA 02/2018 - 04/2018

Math and Computer Science Tutor

- Taught classes to students k-12(10-25 students) in math and computer science.
- Provided customer service, as well as, explained all our services explicitly.

Undergraduate Researcher

Swenson summer physics researcher Conducted paid research using SQL and C++ to understand the Growth of Galaxy Clusters.

Presented completed findings at two research symposiums.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

06/2020

Thousand Oaks, CA 05/2016 - 08/2016

California Lutheran University

Bachelor of Science, Physics

Thousand Oaks, CA 02/2018